Wolchok, Samuel Correspondence and Minutes 5505
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Samuel Wolchok Correspondence and Minutes
1945-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wolchok, Samuel
5505
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents), correspondence, minutes (administrative records).
Proceedings of the United Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Employes Union's General Executive Board meetings from 1945 through 1948, and correspondence, clippings, and memorabilia of President Samuel Wolchok.
3338536
Biographical / Historical
Samuel Wolchok was born in Russia in 1896 and emigrated to the United States in 1912. Wolchok was President of the Untied Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Employees Union from 1937 to 1948. After his presidency, he worked for the CIO and later in industry. He died at the age of 82 in 1979.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of proceedings of the United Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Employes Union's General Executive Board meetings from 1945 through 1948, and correspondence, clippings, and memorabilia of President Samuel Wolchok.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 14, 2019
Labor unions -- Officials and employees; Wolchok, Samuel, 1896-
3338536
- General Executive Board proceedings, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  September 24-29, 1945
- General Executive Board proceedings, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  October 15, 1946
- General Executive Board proceedings, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  October 17-18, 1946
- General Executive Board proceedings, volume I, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  January 27-February 1, 1947
- General Executive Board proceedings, volume II, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- General Executive Board proceedings, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  May 12-16, 1947
- General Executive Board proceedings, volume II, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  November 10-16, 1947
- General Executive Board proceedings, volume III, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- General Executive Board proceedings, volume III, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- General Executive Board proceedings, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  June 15-19, 1948
- Correspondence, 1935-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Correspondents include the Kheel family, Joseph J. Thorndike Jr., John Zellers, Irving Abramson, Harry Truman, Philip Murray, Sidney Hillman, H. J. Gibbons, and others
- Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Correspondents include Harry Brandt, Samuel Heller, George Kirstein, Samuel Feinberg, and Fred Hartley, Jr. Also includes documents related to hearings held on charges filed against Wolchok, alleging that the Greater New York CIO Council violated the CIO Constitution and Rules for Industrial Councils.
- Clippings, 1941-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Contains clippings in Yiddish
- Investigation of Communism in New York City distributive trades, hearings, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Memorabilia, 1945-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)